<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.4.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://andrei-migunov.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><link href="https://andrei-migunov.github.io/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en"/><updated>2025-08-11T16:36:57+00:00</updated><id>https://andrei-migunov.github.io/feed.xml</id><title type="html">blank</title><subtitle>A simple, whitespace theme for academics. Based on [*folio](https://github.com/bogoli/-folio) design. </subtitle><entry><title type="html">Deafheaven - Lonely People With Power</title><link href="https://andrei-migunov.github.io/blog/2025/Deafheaven/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Deafheaven - Lonely People With Power"/><published>2025-04-18T07:57:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-04-18T07:57:00+00:00</updated><id>https://andrei-migunov.github.io/blog/2025/Deafheaven</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://andrei-migunov.github.io/blog/2025/Deafheaven/"><![CDATA[<p>Deafheaven’s new album, <i>Lonely People With Power</i>, is the album of the year for me.</p> <p>I played in a “shoegaze” band with friends after highschool. It primed me to appreciate a certain attitude to vocals - that they were not all that special in the grand scheme of things, that they had a role to play in a song that undoubtedly goes beyond the conveying of lyrics and leading a melody, and they are not merely supported by a bunch of tertiary instruments who are second fiddle.<i>Sunbather</i> was the first black metal album I’d ever heard. I remember loving it, and being frustrated by the idiotic purism that made up much of the criticism towards that album - from black metal elitists obsessed with their genre’s terrible production and the ‘authenticity’ this is supposed to convey. George Clarke’s vocals are texturally powerful and align with the band’s music perfectly. Sunbather’s melodies were sweet and melancholy, and the new album does this even better, and with greater diversity. Its subject matter is exciting and compelling. Until LPWP, my favorite Deafheaven had been <i>New Bermuda</i>. The riffs are incredible, he has the voice of a wildcat. I have probably listened to it many more times than Sunbather at this point. Deafheaven makes music whose purpose is to be art. It is not some sad byproduct of half-hearted disavowed “I could care less what you think” music. They have made great art in LPWP. I don’t know if they would describe it this way. I don’t mean anything high minded by ‘art’ - just that it is to be felt, and isn’t selling itself short or disavowing the magnitude of feeling it means to convey. Most hardcore, for what it’s worth, does. I love hardcore, I listen to it every single day - but it is in some sense more utlitarian and doesn’t usually set the bar high. That’s totally ok, and part of what makes it endearing. Metal often aims for ‘art’ in my sense, and I appreciate that in some ways more.</p> <p>If you like metal, you surely have listened to it already. If you want to like metal, it might be a place you can start. I think eventually a person has to get over themselves and enjoy music with harsh vocals, past a certain point refusing it on the grounds of “I don’t like screaming” is philistinism. I sound harsh, maybe, but indeed this common attitude towards such music, as opposed to say classical or country music which are also sometimes not people’s main thing, is uniquely stark. My life is better for my enjoyment - my sometimes actively/consciously-nurtured capacity to enjoy genres based on harsh vocals and distortion. My life is also better for liking blast beats and playing the riff at the beginning of ‘Black Brick’ literally every time I pick up a guitar. After all, harsh vocal styles have been around for a long time in subcultural music - longer than most of us have been alive, now. It is a massive umbrella of different styles, probably as internally varied as is the sum of what lies <em>outside</em> that umbrella. It is worth the time, and worth it to cultivate the desire, to overcome one’s aversion. I listened to Converge’s <i>Jane Doe</i> not because I liked it at first, but because everyone I knew did, and I was able to understand even then that this meant I <i>probably should, too</i>. It was the right choice - and I am grateful I made an effort to like it. It paid off, and opened many other avenues of musical and artistic enjoyment for me. Indeed, I’ve never been convincd by someone saying that some music was not worth listening to and trying to enjoy. That’s not a route I’ve ever taken - everything deserves a chance.</p> <p>Hegel describes the ‘beginnings’ of science as vulgar empiricism. We can’t have theories, reasons, etc. without some simple exposure. After exposure, we can make a plan for how to approach it. Scientific method for this reason can’t really exist as one general scheme: objects tell us how to study them, not the other way around. The appreciation of art is no different.</p> <p>In classic dialectical fashion, I came around to clean vocal styles in metal only much later. Now I consider, for example, Pallbearer a beloved and favorite band (actually - I first saw Pallebearer open for Deafheaven in like 2015 - I bought <i>Sorrow and Extinction</i> and stayed up until 3am on a work night listening to it on repeat, just completely electrified by its slow, heavy, drama and clean vocals that I could never have appreciated until that day. The mournful melody charged with a visible effort that the vocalist made to reach the notes. It was extremely profound to me at the time, visceral and emotional, to watch him strive to hit the notes he was aiming for. As someone too shy to sing a single note in front of another person, his vulnerability was a big deal to me. By the way, he was great - it was just clear how much he worked for that).</p> <p>Anyway, I’d listen to the whole thing front to back in this case: but if you’re not sure, I think ‘Winona’ is the crown jewel:</p> <p><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=qbt2B65JPEY" title="Winona"><img src="https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/3/37/Lonely_People_with_Power_Deafheaven_album_cover.jpg" alt="Lonely People With Power"/></a></p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Deafheaven’s new album, Lonely People With Power, is the album of the year for me.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">AFI - Fall Children</title><link href="https://andrei-migunov.github.io/blog/2024/AFI/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="AFI - Fall Children"/><published>2024-10-31T07:57:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-10-31T07:57:00+00:00</updated><id>https://andrei-migunov.github.io/blog/2024/AFI</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://andrei-migunov.github.io/blog/2024/AFI/"><![CDATA[<p>My sources tell me that tonight is the first night that Des Moines kids get to trick or treat on Halloween rather than on so-called ‘beggars’ night’. I guess I think trick or treating on some day that isn’t Halloween is like drinking coke zero. To want the aesthetic experience without the mischief and minor vandalism strikes me as wrong.</p> <p>Anyway. Undoubtedly, <i> All Hallows </i> is one of the best AFI records - and it’s just an EP! And one of the songs is one of the best Misfits covers ever recorded! However, <i>Fall Children</i> (below) takes the cake.</p> <p><i> Sing the Sorrow </i> got me into AFI when I was about 12 years old or so. The <i>All Hallows</i> EP shored that up, in particular this song. This band ‘changed my life’ in a way that happens a lot more when you’re that young. Downstream of this are all of my musical preferences that persist to this day. The Halloween vibes of this album are classic, and immaculate. Happy Halloween!</p> <p><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Uco1mDpfIuM"><img src="https://www.reddit.com/r/vinyl/comments/14kx6j5/afi_all_hallows_ep/" alt="AFI - All Hallows EP (full)"/></a></p> ]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[My sources tell me that tonight is the first night that Des Moines kids get to trick or treat on Halloween rather than on so-called ‘beggars’ night’. I guess I think trick or treating on some day that isn’t Halloween is like drinking coke zero. To want the aesthetic experience without the mischief and minor vandalism strikes me as wrong.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">CRN, ODE, and PP Examples</title><link href="https://andrei-migunov.github.io/blog/2024/CRNODEExamples/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="CRN, ODE, and PP Examples"/><published>2024-04-10T12:57:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-04-10T12:57:00+00:00</updated><id>https://andrei-migunov.github.io/blog/2024/CRNODEExamples</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://andrei-migunov.github.io/blog/2024/CRNODEExamples/"><![CDATA[<p>Download these notes here: <a href="https://andrei-migunov.github.io/assets/jupyter/Examples.ipynb" title="download">Examples</a></p> <div class="jupyter-notebook" style="position: relative; width: 100%; margin: 0 auto;"> <div class="jupyter-notebook-iframe-container"> <iframe src="/assets/jupyter/Examples.ipynb.html" style="position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; border-style: none;" width="100%" height="100%" onload="this.parentElement.style.paddingBottom = (this.contentWindow.document.documentElement.scrollHeight + 10) + 'px'"></iframe> </div> </div>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[A growing list of examples relating to CRNs, ODEs, PPs]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">CRN to GPAC Tutorial</title><link href="https://andrei-migunov.github.io/blog/2024/CRNtoODE/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="CRN to GPAC Tutorial"/><published>2024-02-23T12:57:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-02-23T12:57:00+00:00</updated><id>https://andrei-migunov.github.io/blog/2024/CRNtoODE</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://andrei-migunov.github.io/blog/2024/CRNtoODE/"><![CDATA[<p>(to be updated, over time). Download these notes here: <a href="https://andrei-migunov.github.io/assets/jupyter/ODEs_tutorial.ipynb" title="download">CRN-GPAC Tutorial</a></p> <div class="jupyter-notebook" style="position: relative; width: 100%; margin: 0 auto;"> <div class="jupyter-notebook-iframe-container"> <iframe src="/assets/jupyter/ODEs_tutorial.ipynb.html" style="position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; border-style: none;" width="100%" height="100%" onload="this.parentElement.style.paddingBottom = (this.contentWindow.document.documentElement.scrollHeight + 10) + 'px'"></iframe> </div> </div>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[CRN to GPAC Tutorial]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Gizmo</title><link href="https://andrei-migunov.github.io/blog/2024/gizmo/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Gizmo"/><published>2024-01-19T12:57:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-01-19T12:57:00+00:00</updated><id>https://andrei-migunov.github.io/blog/2024/gizmo</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://andrei-migunov.github.io/blog/2024/gizmo/"><![CDATA[<figure> <picture> <img src="/assets/img/gizmo3.jpeg" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> <p>This little creature is Gizmo. My mom found him outside of her workplace - she and her coworkers take care of the cats nearby. He was the smallest of the bunch, shaking, freezing. Most of his siblings hiss, but he came up to my mom and leaned against her leg, so she brought him home.</p> <p>A couple more pictures of Gizmo, below. The following picture is Mara. She’s an angel. I was surprised my landlord during grad school let me keep her in my apartment. She was my roommate during gradschool, and I love her so much. She actually did most of my dissertation work (I can now admit this without any liability). The last picture is Christopher, my first pet. He was very old, and grumpy, and passed recently. We miss him.</p> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <img src="/assets/img/gizmo.jpg" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <img src="/assets/img/gizmo2.jpeg" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <img src="/assets/img/mara.jpeg" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <img src="/assets/img/christopher.jpeg" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="cats"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Cormac McCarthy on mathematics, specialization</title><link href="https://andrei-migunov.github.io/blog/2024/mccarthy-math-copy/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Cormac McCarthy on mathematics, specialization"/><published>2024-01-14T12:57:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-01-14T12:57:00+00:00</updated><id>https://andrei-migunov.github.io/blog/2024/mccarthy-math%20copy</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://andrei-migunov.github.io/blog/2024/mccarthy-math-copy/"><![CDATA[<blockquote> <p>“Working on a mathematics problem, sometimes for a long time - it’s like a lost animal coming in from the rain. You just wanna say ‘There you are… I was worried about you.’ “. (Cormac McCarthy)</p> </blockquote> <p>Part of what I like about Cormac McCarthy is that he was interested in everything and dived into whatever he felt like (physics, architecture, whatever), and did not shy away from giving an opinion on it. We should all aspire to be more like this (within reason, of course). Someone who is genuinely interested in the world doesn’t need to worry about coming off as ‘outside their lane’ - the requisite humility and gentleness of assertion come naturally. In any case, how much more in-your-lane does it get than going out of your way to allow those in other areas to teach and inform you? Not to say there aren’t also boring people who consider their being boring morally upright.</p> <p>It reminds me that what I often find interesting about experts and specialists is much less their expertise, but how they map the domain-specific prejudices and ontology of their field to other areas, which is often exciting and thoughtful and original, if often scientifically inadequate. Trotsky (<i> Philosophical Notebooks </i>) and Hegel (<i>the Encyclopedia Logic </i>) pointed out that specialists sometimes import their worldview into places where it does not belong and cannot make sense of things. Trotsky accused (and he’s not wrong) Mendeleev of being fairly conservative in a particular kind of way on ‘social change’ despite being a brilliant scientist, and correlated the two this way.</p> <p>This lines up with another Hegelian insight that the right way to study a thing is given by that thing, not from without: methods come from the object. I often try to reason about non-computational phenomena (sociological, political, whatever) in terms of complexity and computability and so on. The metaphors are nice, but they are often not much more than that. Someone who insisted they were deeper would have their work cut out for them and would probably end up embarrassed. But this doesn’t mean we shouldn’t try just for the fun of it - in a lighthearted way, with a low perception of the stakes. Metaphors and analogies are <i>good</i> things to have, and it is good to come to science equipped with many of them.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="mathematics,"/><category term="pets,"/><category term="specialization"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[“Working on a mathematics problem, sometimes for a long time - it’s like a lost animal coming in from the rain. You just wanna say ‘There you are… I was worried about you.’ “. (Cormac McCarthy)]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">I-think beliefs</title><link href="https://andrei-migunov.github.io/blog/2024/lichtenberg/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="I-think beliefs"/><published>2024-01-05T12:57:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-01-05T12:57:00+00:00</updated><id>https://andrei-migunov.github.io/blog/2024/lichtenberg</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://andrei-migunov.github.io/blog/2024/lichtenberg/"><![CDATA[<p>I’m always interested in what people think they are doing when they argue about politics with people who are not their collaborators, comrades, etc - that is, people with whom they are engaged in a shared political effort. This goes double for the internet: what could one <i> possibly </i> believe will happen when they argue in the comments of an instagram reel?</p> <p>If they want to convince others of their view can it be said that they think their view matters? <i> Can </i> that be said of most views and holders of views? Would the world be any different, at all, if you believed the opposite of what you believe about X, or caused someone else to? Are most such claims of the form “if I thought this were attainable, and I don’t, then I’d treat it as fact and with greater urgency”? At the same time, many other belief-havers can be called ‘worshippers of established fact’ - that is, their belief revolves primarily around political acts accomplished long ago, and their political <i>activity</i> is simply the routine management of an already hegemonic political or ideological tendency - having nothing to do with politics, in any substantive way, at all. All these people have to their name is that their view happens to be the dominant one, though largely not due to their own activity. In either case, the relevant thing is one’s <i>actual</i> position in the world (in fact, one’s action is the surest expression of one’s actual belief - in the sense of Hegel), one’s actual ability to enact one’s beliefs (or at least to have some established, hegemonic political quasi-deity do it for you), or the actual state of affairs.</p> <p>I generally am respectful of seriousness - including in those who I disagree with. This is not to say I respect the content of their views, and I usually consider it a disingenuous lie when people pretend they respect the contents of other views that differ extremely from theirs, especially on matters of virtue, simply so that they can be a good pluralist (I don’t think good pluralism requires this lie). After all, do you hold your views because they’re just as good as some other ones and you flipped a coin? I do not respect transphobia or consider it a viable competing perspective or <i>alternative research programme</i>, in adults I consider it a failure of character, and I am hostile to the treatment of others that position very clearly entails.</p> <p>I have a similar attitude toward phrases like “I think…”. Do you really merely <i> think </i> X? I am guilty of this myself at times, when I do not want to pick a fight (rather, when I think someone else would unless I preemptively backed down rhetorically in this way by distancing myself from myself). For example, I do not merely think that human beings ought to strive for a society free from coersion. This is a very vague statement that needs a lot of elaboration and delicacy, but it’s not something that is up in the air for me - I don’t think it (that is, I don’t speak about it as something “I think”), it is a knowledge claim, and it corresponds to my character and how I (try to) live my life. It would be hard for you to disprove that I think it, which is why people hide behind such “I think” language all the time on matters that they know they have no uncertainty about. Whether you can disprove the claim itself is the substantive challenge it should pose to you - and to me, to elaborate it carefully.</p> <p>At the same time, the only good philosophy of science out there tells us that people we disagree with might make progress in defense of their views later, and there isn’t going to be a formulaic way to determine who that is. So if you’re serious about something, you treat it as knowledge and this also entails certain behavior from you: you are obligated to defend these knowledge claims in the way a “mere thinker” isn’t. You will meet equally stubborn people. Sometimes your differences will matter and they will make your blood boil. Sometimes you can all laugh at your shared impotence to change the world in the ways you want to. You rarely need to hem-and-haw over it. Most people will treat you with respect or, often, are only disrespectful out of the insecurity of their own impotence.</p> <p>I came across this quote not too long ago, and I like it very much:</p> <blockquote> <p>I ceased in the year 1764 to believe that one can convince one’s opponents with arguments printed in books. It is not to do that, therefore, that I have taken up my pen, but merely so as to annoy them, and to bestow strength and courage on those on our own side, and to make it known to the others that they have not convinced us. (Georg Lichtenberg)</p> </blockquote>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="belief"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Lichtenberg]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">anything goes</title><link href="https://andrei-migunov.github.io/blog/2023/feyerabend/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="anything goes"/><published>2023-12-29T12:57:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-12-29T12:57:00+00:00</updated><id>https://andrei-migunov.github.io/blog/2023/feyerabend</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://andrei-migunov.github.io/blog/2023/feyerabend/"><![CDATA[<p>I’m a very big fan of philosopher of science Paul Feyerabend. I admire his ideas and largely agree with them, and I adore his humor (which is the best quality of a philosopher and comes out especially in his letters with Imre Lakatos - the collection of these letters is available as <i>For and Against Method</i>). Ian James Kidd wrote a great article during the tail end of the pandemic linked below, with an excerpt on Feyerabend’s (in)famous phrase “anything goes”.</p> <p>Ian James Kidd (https://medium.com/@ian.kidd/following-the-science-some-feyerabendian-reflections-c85a4bab7c98)</p> <blockquote> <p>‘Anything goes’ actually meant something quite different. It doesn’t mean scientists can use any methods they like, or none. It doesn’t mean caprice should replace carefulness. It does not mean scientific practice consists of a constant whirl of creativity and innovation. Scientific practice, across its forms, is often ploddingly procedural — something that Feyerabend, as a trained physicist, knew all too well. ‘Anything goes’ was, he explained, the reaction of a methodological monist to the actual history and practice of the sciences. Methodological monism, the doctrine that there’s a single unified set of fully articulated methodological rules, which don’t change over time and apply to all sciences, whether the topic is supernovae or starfish. Feyerabend objected that if monists will insist on identifying some invariant rule, then the only one they can find across the history of the sciences would be that ‘anything goes’. But there’s a more sensible alternative: one can abandon the limits of monism and embrace a more complex and pluralistic image of science that recognises that its methods and goals vary enormously.</p> </blockquote>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="philosophy"/><category term="of"/><category term="science"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Ian James Kidd on Feyerabend]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">jupyter test post</title><link href="https://andrei-migunov.github.io/blog/2023/attempt/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="jupyter test post"/><published>2023-12-24T12:57:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-12-24T12:57:00+00:00</updated><id>https://andrei-migunov.github.io/blog/2023/attempt</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://andrei-migunov.github.io/blog/2023/attempt/"><![CDATA[<p>To include a jupyter notebook in a post, you can use the following code:</p> <div class="language-html highlighter-rouge"><div class="highlight"><pre class="highlight"><code>{::nomarkdown}
{% assign jupyter_path = "assets/jupyter/jupytesting.ipynb" | relative_url %}
{% capture notebook_exists %}{% file_exists assets/jupyter/jupytesting.ipynb %}{% endcapture %}
{% if notebook_exists == "true" %}
    {% jupyter_notebook jupyter_path %}
{% else %}
    <span class="nt">&lt;p&gt;</span>Sorry, the notebook you are looking for does not exist.<span class="nt">&lt;/p&gt;</span>
{% endif %}
{:/nomarkdown}
</code></pre></div></div> <div class="jupyter-notebook" style="position: relative; width: 100%; margin: 0 auto;"> <div class="jupyter-notebook-iframe-container"> <iframe src="/assets/jupyter/jupytesting.ipynb.html" style="position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; border-style: none;" width="100%" height="100%" onload="this.parentElement.style.paddingBottom = (this.contentWindow.document.documentElement.scrollHeight + 10) + 'px'"></iframe> </div> </div>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="posting"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[this is an attempt by me to use this website (dangerous)]]></summary></entry></feed>